<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infrastructure on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/tags/infrastructure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infrastructure on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2024, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/tags/infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Antares: The Next Generation in Digital Tax Administration and Banking Core Systems</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2025-10-09-antares-la-proxima-generacion-en-sistemas-centrales-de-administracion-tributaria-y-banca-digital/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2025-10-09-antares-la-proxima-generacion-en-sistemas-centrales-de-administracion-tributaria-y-banca-digital/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an era defined by digital transformation, public financial institutions and tax administrations are under increasing pressure to modernize their legacy systems. The need for efficiency, transparency, and enhanced service delivery has never been greater. Enter &lt;strong&gt;Antares&lt;/strong&gt;, a robust, flexible, and forward-looking software solution engineered to serve as the foundational core for both tax authorities and banking institutions. Built with modern, sustainable technologies and designed for longevity, Antares represents a paradigm shift in how financial governance systems are conceived and implemented. This document provides a comprehensive overview of the Antares system, detailing its core functionalities, advanced technical architecture, and the practical pathways to its implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Collection in Tax and Financial Administration: Strategies and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-05-06-dominando-la-recaudacion-en-la-administracion-tributaria-financiera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-05-06-dominando-la-recaudacion-en-la-administracion-tributaria-financiera/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Effective collection in tax and financial administration is crucial for maintaining a healthy financial position and ensuring the smooth operation of an organization. However, collecting outstanding debts can be a challenging task, often requiring a strategic approach and a deep understanding of the various factors that influence collection success. In this blog post, we will explore some key strategies and best practices to improve collection in tax and financial administration.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing the Impact of Artificial Intelligence on Tax Administration Operations</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-04-29-inteligencia-artificial-e-impuestos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-04-29-inteligencia-artificial-e-impuestos/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;In the realm of Tax Administrations, the integration of Artificial Intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing traditional practices, offering a myriad of benefits across various operational areas. As a professional blog writer, let&amp;rsquo;s delve into the key areas that stand to benefit the most from the implementation of AI in tax administration operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enhanced-taxpayer-experience&#34;&gt;Enhanced Taxpayer Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI technologies are reshaping the taxpayer experience by providing faster, more responsive service through natural language processing and machine learning. Virtual assistants equipped with AI capabilities offer compliance-by-design tax systems, alerting taxpayers to errors and ensuring smoother interactions with tax authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
