<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Developing World on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/tags/developing-world/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Developing World on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2024, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/tags/developing-world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Effective Tax Administration in the Developing World: Strategies for Maximizing Revenue with Limited Resources</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-10-administracion-tributaria-eficaz-paises-vias-desarrollo-estrategias-maximizar-ingresos-recursos-limitados/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-10-administracion-tributaria-eficaz-paises-vias-desarrollo-estrategias-maximizar-ingresos-recursos-limitados/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Tax administration is a crucial component of any government&#39;s fiscal policy, as it provides the necessary revenue to fund public services and infrastructure. However, in the developing world, tax administration often faces significant challenges due to limited resources, corruption, and inadequate infrastructure. In this blog post, we will explore the key areas to prioritize when aiming to improve tax collection with minimal resources and discuss the sole area that should be set as the priority in extreme cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenges-in-tax-administration-in-the-developing-world&#34;&gt;Challenges in Tax Administration in the Developing World&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tax administration in the developing world is often plagued by several challenges, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Limited Resources&lt;/em&gt;: Many developing countries have limited financial resources, which hinders their ability to invest in effective tax administration systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Corruption&lt;/em&gt;: Corruption is a significant obstacle to effective tax administration, as it can lead to tax evasion and undermine public trust in the government.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inadequate Infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;: Inadequate infrastructure, such as lack of technology and inadequate transportation networks, can hinder the efficient collection of taxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prioritizing-areas-for-improved-tax-collection&#34;&gt;Prioritizing Areas for Improved Tax Collection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To improve tax collection with minimal resources, the following areas should be prioritized:
Simplification of Tax Laws: Simplifying tax laws can make it easier for taxpayers to comply with tax regulations, reducing the likelihood of errors and disputes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enhanced Taxpayer Education&lt;/em&gt;: Educating taxpayers about their tax obligations can increase compliance and reduce tax evasion.
Improved Taxpayer Service: Providing excellent taxpayer service can increase taxpayer satisfaction and trust in the tax administration system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Effective Tax Audit and Enforcement&lt;/em&gt;: Conducting regular tax audits and enforcing tax laws can help to identify and address tax evasion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technology Adoption&lt;/em&gt;: Adopting technology, such as electronic filing and payment systems, can streamline tax collection and reduce costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prioritizing-in-extreme-cases&#34;&gt;Prioritizing in Extreme Cases&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In extreme cases where resources are severely limited, the sole area that should be set as the priority is:
Taxpayer Education: Educating taxpayers about their tax obligations is crucial in extreme cases, as it can increase compliance and reduce tax evasion. This can be achieved through public awareness campaigns, tax workshops, and other educational initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effective tax administration is critical for the fiscal sustainability of any government. In the developing world, where resources are limited, prioritizing the right areas can help to maximize revenue collection. By simplifying tax laws, enhancing taxpayer education, improving taxpayer service, conducting effective tax audits and enforcement, and adopting technology, governments can improve tax collection with minimal resources. In extreme cases, taxpayer education should be the sole area of focus to increase compliance and reduce tax evasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written with the support of &lt;a href=&#34;https://perplexity.ai&#34;&gt;perplexity.ai&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;chat.bing.com&#34;&gt;chat.bing.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you Patric Tarraf for your help in addressing countries in the proper way!&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Risks of a Lacking Integrated Tax System (ITAS) in Detecting Tax Fraud</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-03-los-riesgos-de-carecer-de-itas-para-detectar-fraude-fiscal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-03-los-riesgos-de-carecer-de-itas-para-detectar-fraude-fiscal/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Tax fraud is a significant issue that affects economies worldwide, with estimates suggesting it accounts for between 4% and 15% of the tax gap in various OECD countries&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Combating tax fraud is crucial for maintaining the integrity of tax systems and ensuring governments receive the revenue needed to fund public services. In recent years, tax authorities have increasingly adopted integrated tax administration systems, including artificial intelligence (AI), to enhance their ability to detect and prevent tax fraud. However, the lack of such systems can severely hinder the effectiveness of tax authorities in this endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-importance-of-integrated-tax-administration-systems&#34;&gt;The Importance of Integrated Tax Administration Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ITAS are designed to automate and streamline tax administration processes, making it easier for tax authorities to detect and prevent tax fraud&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. These systems can analyze large amounts of data quickly and accurately, identifying patterns and anomalies that may indicate fraudulent activity. For instance, AI-powered systems can analyze financial transactions, income, and asset declarations to identify discrepancies that may suggest tax evasion&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;successful-examples-of-integrated-tax-administration-systems&#34;&gt;Successful Examples of Integrated Tax Administration Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several countries have successfully implemented integrated tax administration systems to combat tax fraud. India&#39;s Income Tax Department uses AI to identify fraudulent applications for input tax credits via false GST registrations&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref2:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Singapore&#39;s Inland Revenue Authority has developed an in-house network visualizer with a graph database to analyze intricate relationships between entities during audits and investigations&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref3:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. These systems have been instrumental in identifying and preventing tax fraud, resulting in significant increases in tax revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-risks-of-a-lacking-itas&#34;&gt;The Risks of a Lacking ITAS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lack of integrated tax administration systems can significantly hinder the ability of tax authorities to detect and prevent tax fraud. Without these systems, tax authorities are forced to rely on manual processes, which are time-consuming, labor-intensive, and prone to errors&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This can lead to a significant delay in identifying and addressing tax fraud, allowing fraudsters to continue evading taxes and undermining the integrity of the tax system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-consequences-of-inadequate-tax-administration-systems&#34;&gt;The Consequences of Inadequate Tax Administration Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consequences of inadequate tax administration systems can be severe. Tax fraud can lead to significant revenue losses for governments, which can have a negative impact on public services and the overall economy&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref2:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Additionally, tax fraud can undermine public trust in the tax system, leading to a decrease in compliance rates and further exacerbating the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-need-for-effective-integrated-tax-administration-systems&#34;&gt;The Need for Effective Integrated Tax Administration Systems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the lack of integrated tax administration systems can significantly hinder the ability of tax authorities to detect and prevent tax fraud. The adoption of AI and other digital technologies is crucial for enhancing the effectiveness of tax administration systems and ensuring governments receive the revenue needed to fund public services&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref4:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Tax authorities must prioritize the development and implementation of these systems to combat tax fraud and maintain the integrity of the tax system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written with the support of &lt;a href=&#34;https://perplexity.ai&#34;&gt;perplexity.ai&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;chat.bing.com&#34;&gt;chat.bing.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jdintl.econ.queensu.ca/publications/qed_dp_123.pdf&#34;&gt;http://jdintl.econ.queensu.ca/publications/qed_dp_123.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crownagents.com/project/integrated-tax-administration-system-itas/&#34;&gt;https://www.crownagents.com/project/integrated-tax-administration-system-itas/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref4:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.egovja.com/integrated-computerized-tax-administration-system-ictas/&#34;&gt;https://www.egovja.com/integrated-computerized-tax-administration-system-ictas/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Tax Administration Challenges in Developing Countries</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-05-20-superando-desafios-de-administracion-tributaria-paises-desarrollo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-05-20-superando-desafios-de-administracion-tributaria-paises-desarrollo/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Tax administration in developing countries faces significant challenges in collecting revenue efficiently and equitably. Low tax-to-GDP ratios, high rates of informality, limited taxpayer compliance, and outdated technology all hinder the ability of tax authorities to mobilize domestic resources. However, with the right reforms and investments, these obstacles can be overcome to strengthen fiscal capacity and support economic development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-promise-and-limitations-of-technology&#34;&gt;The Promise and Limitations of Technology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology has immense potential to transform tax administration in developing countries by improving taxpayer identification, enhancing compliance monitoring, and facilitating voluntary compliance&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Digital tools like electronic fiscal devices, e-filing, and e-payments can help tax authorities create comprehensive taxpayer databases, automatically cross-check reported liabilities against third-party data, and provide convenient services to taxpayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, realizing the full benefits of technology requires overcoming significant barriers. Inadequate infrastructure like electricity and internet access can lead to system failures and user frustration, especially for small businesses and rural taxpayers. Resistance from taxpayers and tax officials, lack of institutional strategy, and outdated regulatory frameworks also limit the impact of new technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address these challenges, tax authorities should adopt a multi-pronged approach. Investing in basic infrastructure and offering alternative solutions like offline filing for underserved groups can mitigate access issues. Robust change management, targeted training, and assistance can help overcome human resistance. Sequencing reforms, cleaning up data, and retraining staff should precede technology rollouts. Policymakers should also update regulations for data sharing and cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;improving-compliance-through-behavioral-insights&#34;&gt;Improving Compliance through Behavioral Insights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compliance is a major challenge in developing countries, with high rates of tax evasion and avoidance. Households and firms often underreport income, especially for activities that are harder for authorities to observe. Complexity and lack of awareness also lead to unintentional noncompliance&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behavioral insights offer promising solutions. Simplifying tax processes, providing clear information, and sending reminders can significantly boost compliance. For example, SMS reminders increased tax payments by 6% in Uganda, while simplified information decreased late payments by 23% in Belgium&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adjusting tax policies can also encourage compliance. Bachas and Soto&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref2:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; found that increasing corporate taxes on profits in Costa Rica led firms to evade by inflating reported costs, suggesting revenue taxes as an alternative. Londono-Velez and Avila-Mehecha&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref3:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; showed that improved information on offshore accounts and amnesty programs had large impacts on wealth tax compliance in Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, not all noncompliance is strategic. Brockmeyer et al.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref4:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; found that failure to pay property taxes in Mexico was often due to limited liquidity rather than evasion. Policymakers should consider taxpayers&#39; circumstances and use a mix of incentives, simplification, and enforcement to promote compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strengthening-tax-administration-capacity&#34;&gt;Strengthening Tax Administration Capacity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing countries face extensive political, economic and administrative challenges in closing tax gaps&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Weak institutional capacity, lack of skilled staff, and corruption undermine the effectiveness of tax administrations&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Reforms are often difficult due to vested interests and resistance to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building sustainable capacity requires a long-term, holistic approach. Investing in human capital through training and performance management is crucial. Organizational restructuring, risk-based audits, and large taxpayer units can improve efficiency. Enhancing taxpayer services and communication can increase voluntary compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political leadership and a whole-of-government approach are essential for successful reforms. Policymakers should champion modernization, align tax policies with development goals, and coordinate with other agencies. Engaging stakeholders, managing change, and monitoring progress are also key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;leveraging-international-cooperation&#34;&gt;Leveraging International Cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an increasingly globalized world, international cooperation is vital for tackling cross-border tax challenges. Aggressive tax planning and transfer mispricing by multinational corporations lead to huge revenue losses for developing countries, far exceeding foreign aid. Tax incentives, though ineffective at attracting investment, still result in significant forgone revenue&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The international community has taken steps to address these issues, such as the OECD&#39;s Base Erosion and Profit Shifting (BEPS) project and the Addis Tax Initiative. However, more action is needed to ensure that developing countries can fully participate in and benefit from global tax reforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed countries and international organizations should provide technical assistance, capacity building, and financial support to help developing countries strengthen their tax systems. Sharing best practices, facilitating knowledge exchange, and supporting regional cooperation can also accelerate progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, domestic revenue mobilization is a shared responsibility. By working together to overcome challenges and build effective, equitable tax systems, developed and developing countries can unlock the resources needed to achieve sustainable development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written with the support of &lt;a href=&#34;https://perplexity.ai&#34;&gt;perplexity.ai&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;chat.bing.com&#34;&gt;chat.bing.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.worldbank.org/en/developmenttalk/promise-and-limitations-information-technology-tax-mobilization&#34;&gt;https://blogs.worldbank.org/en/developmenttalk/promise-and-limitations-information-technology-tax-mobilization&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.worldbank.org/en/impactevaluations/increasing-tax-revenue-developing-countries&#34;&gt;https://blogs.worldbank.org/en/impactevaluations/increasing-tax-revenue-developing-countries&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref4:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/etudes/etudes/join/2014/433849/EXPO-DEVE_ET%282014%29433849_EN.pdf&#34;&gt;https://www.europarl.europa.eu/RegData/etudes/etudes/join/2014/433849/EXPO-DEVE_ET%282014%29433849_EN.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jota.website/article/view/8&#34;&gt;http://jota.website/article/view/8&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
