<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Developing World on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/tags/developing-world/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Developing World on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2024, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/tags/developing-world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Transformative Power of Data in Tax Administration</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-07-08-el-poder-transformador-de-los-datos-en-la-administracion-tributaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-07-08-el-poder-transformador-de-los-datos-en-la-administracion-tributaria/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h2 id=&#34;the-importance-of-data-within-a-tax-administration-system-in-the-developing-world&#34;&gt;The Importance of Data within a Tax Administration System in the Developing World&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the developing world, tax administrations often face significant challenges in effectively collecting revenue and ensuring compliance. One of the key factors that can help address these challenges is the strategic use of data within the tax administration system&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accurate and comprehensive data is essential for tax authorities to identify the true tax base, monitor compliance, and facilitate efficient tax collection. In developing countries, where the informal economy and tax evasion are prevalent, leveraging data can be a game-changer.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Income Tax Collection: Strategies for Revenue Administrations</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-07-01-mejorando-la-recaudacion-del-impuesto-sobre-la-rentaganancias-estrategias-para-las-administraciones-tributarias/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-07-01-mejorando-la-recaudacion-del-impuesto-sobre-la-rentaganancias-estrategias-para-las-administraciones-tributarias/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;As a revenue administration, collecting income tax effectively is crucial for funding public services and driving economic growth. However, many countries struggle with low compliance rates and inefficient collection processes. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore key strategies to enhance income tax collection, drawing insights from successful reforms in various countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;simplifying-the-tax-system&#34;&gt;Simplifying the Tax System&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most effective ways to improve income tax collection is by simplifying the tax system. Georgia&amp;rsquo;s experience illustrates this well. After the 2003 Rose Revolution, the government simplified the tax code, reduced rates, and eliminated minor local taxes that generated little revenue. The number of taxes was reduced from 21 to just 7, and many rates were lowered. This made the system more transparent and easier for taxpayers to understand and comply with&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing Tax Administration with TADAT</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-24-revolucionando-la-administracion-tributaria-con-tadat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-24-revolucionando-la-administracion-tributaria-con-tadat/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Tax administration plays a crucial role in the development of any country. It is responsible for ensuring that taxes are collected and distributed fairly and efficiently, which in turn supports economic growth and social welfare. In recent years, the Tax Administration Diagnostic Assessment Tool (TADAT) has emerged as a powerful framework for evaluating and improving tax administration in developing countries. In this blog post, we will explore the role of TADAT in revolutionizing tax administration in the development world and discuss how it can help maximize results faster.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administration in the Development World: A Key to Achieving OECD Pillar 2 Objectives</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-17-administracion-tributaria-en-el-mundo-en-desarrollo-una-clave-para-alcanzar-los-objetivos-del-pilar-2-de-la-ocde/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-17-administracion-tributaria-en-el-mundo-en-desarrollo-una-clave-para-alcanzar-los-objetivos-del-pilar-2-de-la-ocde/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Tax administration plays a crucial role in the development of any country. It is responsible for ensuring that taxes are collected and distributed fairly and efficiently, which in turn supports economic growth and social welfare. In recent years, the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) has emphasized the importance of tax administration in achieving its Pillar 2 objectives, which aim to ensure that multinational corporations (MNCs) pay their fair share of taxes. This blog post will explore the relationship between tax administration and OECD Pillar 2 objectives, as well as provide guidance on how to set priorities effectively in the context of tax administration.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Tax Administration in the Developing World: Strategies for Maximizing Revenue with Limited Resources</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-10-administracion-tributaria-eficaz-paises-vias-desarrollo-estrategias-maximizar-ingresos-recursos-limitados/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-10-administracion-tributaria-eficaz-paises-vias-desarrollo-estrategias-maximizar-ingresos-recursos-limitados/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Tax administration is a crucial component of any government&amp;rsquo;s fiscal policy, as it provides the necessary revenue to fund public services and infrastructure. However, in the developing world, tax administration often faces significant challenges due to limited resources, corruption, and inadequate infrastructure. In this blog post, we will explore the key areas to prioritize when aiming to improve tax collection with minimal resources and discuss the sole area that should be set as the priority in extreme cases.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Risks of a Lacking Integrated Tax System (ITAS) in Detecting Tax Fraud</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-03-los-riesgos-de-carecer-de-itas-para-detectar-fraude-fiscal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-03-los-riesgos-de-carecer-de-itas-para-detectar-fraude-fiscal/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Tax fraud is a significant issue that affects economies worldwide, with estimates suggesting it accounts for between 4% and 15% of the tax gap in various OECD countries&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Combating tax fraud is crucial for maintaining the integrity of tax systems and ensuring governments receive the revenue needed to fund public services. In recent years, tax authorities have increasingly adopted integrated tax administration systems, including artificial intelligence (AI), to enhance their ability to detect and prevent tax fraud. However, the lack of such systems can severely hinder the effectiveness of tax authorities in this endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Tax Administration Challenges in Developing Countries</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-05-20-superando-desafios-de-administracion-tributaria-paises-desarrollo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-05-20-superando-desafios-de-administracion-tributaria-paises-desarrollo/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Tax administration in developing countries faces significant challenges in collecting revenue efficiently and equitably. Low tax-to-GDP ratios, high rates of informality, limited taxpayer compliance, and outdated technology all hinder the ability of tax authorities to mobilize domestic resources. However, with the right reforms and investments, these obstacles can be overcome to strengthen fiscal capacity and support economic development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-promise-and-limitations-of-technology&#34;&gt;The Promise and Limitations of Technology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology has immense potential to transform tax administration in developing countries by improving taxpayer identification, enhancing compliance monitoring, and facilitating voluntary compliance&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Digital tools like electronic fiscal devices, e-filing, and e-payments can help tax authorities create comprehensive taxpayer databases, automatically cross-check reported liabilities against third-party data, and provide convenient services to taxpayers.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
