<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/en/categories/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2021, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/en/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Antares</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/en/post/2021-08-27-antares/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/en/post/2021-08-27-antares/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important part of the general proposal, initiated by the previous posts (in particular the &lt;a href=&#34;https://leobelen.github.io/en/post/2021-08-15-un-manual-de-administracion-tributaria/&#34;&gt;tax administration manual&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://leobelen.github.io/en/post/2021-08-01-un-anteproyecto-de-codigo-tributario-argentino/&#34;&gt;draft Tax Code&lt;/a&gt;)) is the program that can be used to carry it out. Actually, some time ago I developed an Integrated Tax Administration System (ITAS), called Antares, about which there is a demo at the following link &lt;a href=&#34;https://antares.socrates.theworkpc.com&#34;&gt;https://antares.socrates.theworkpc.com&lt;/a&gt;, which is in English and was originally filed with a development bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;architecture&#34;&gt;Architecture&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the beginning, the project was focused as a tool that could meet the following characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be easy to install and test.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;highly parameterizable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;based on free software technologies (such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/&#34;&gt;GNU&lt;/a&gt; license).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of the above, the system works with the following technological components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.postgresql.org&#34;&gt;Postgres&lt;/a&gt; as a database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org&#34;&gt;Python 3&lt;/a&gt; as a programming language, with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; framework as a general service provider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3.org/standards/xml/core&#34;&gt;XML&lt;/a&gt; as the document description language and &lt;a href=&#34;http://xpdl.org&#34;&gt;XPDL&lt;/a&gt; as the workflow description language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; as a deployment technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;components&#34;&gt;Components&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system provides the tools to fully implement an ITAS, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A parameterizable document manager, which allows editing, viewing and printing (the latter not implemented in the demo).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A checking account, which maintains balances, transactions, and calculates interest and penalties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A vector of obligations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A workflow manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you like it and find it useful as an interesting starting point, anything you can contact me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:leobelen@gmail.com&#34;&gt;leobelen@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Tax Administration</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/en/post/2021-08-15-un-manual-de-administracion-tributaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/en/post/2021-08-15-un-manual-de-administracion-tributaria/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;An interesting part of having worked in tax administrations for years is that you learn the general framework and best practices to get the job done. No matter the jurisdiction, at this point many of the problems that all of them present are the same and many times start from the fact that many of its members do not fully understand the reason for their actions. Yes, of course, they clearly see the micro, but many times they fail to see the macro, and thus, the set of tasks may sometimes not be the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it was even more interesting to understand that much of what happens within one of these institutions is not publicly written, and therefore many of their officials are obliged either to &amp;quot;invent the wheel every time&amp;quot;, or to read notes or publications that really teach little (except isolated experiences in other parts of the world) or - if they are very lucky - go to a conference where they can learn something new, if the topic of the conference is really new. Many of the conferences, like everything in life, are only to present a result, but more than anything to make contacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this context, many people who want to learn and improve find themselves with a ceiling and the reality is that in my experience, no matter where in the world they are, the tasks are the same and the management is basically the same. And it turns out that I am not alone in this: in 2015 the International Monetary Fund made available to the public a tool that precisely helps States to estimate progress and use best practices, called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tadat.org&#34;&gt;TADAT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this movement was long celebrated, given that it was now possible to compare tax administrations, in an equitable way, the truth is that there is a lack of a tax administration manual that shows in a didactic, unified and disinterested way the concepts, principles and best practices in the material along with ideas to apply, both for jurisdictions without resources and for those that want to improve every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in this scenario you can access a preview of the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://leobelen.github.io/pdfs/admin_tributaria.pdf&#34;&gt;Administración Tributaria Moderna&lt;/a&gt; (in Spanish).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you like it and find it useful as an interesting starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Project for an Argentine Tax Code</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/en/post/2021-08-01-un-anteproyecto-de-codigo-tributario-argentino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/en/post/2021-08-01-un-anteproyecto-de-codigo-tributario-argentino/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Despite the changes proposed by the Central Administration, it is clear that one of the most important problems of current Argentine taxation is aging: The Tax Procedure act (numbered 11.683), was sanctioned in the 1930s, having its last revision in 1998. As a result, many of the solutions it proposes are outdated (for example, there were no computer systems at the time) or have changed so much that they are difficult to recognize (for example, the tax execution process).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make matters worse, there is a wide range of rules that regulate this activity, from laws and decrees to general DGI / AFIP resolutions, and even doctrine, since many concepts require clarification by the enforcement authorities. Projects such as the AFIP electronic library, created at the end of the 90s, or SAIJ, prior in time, have made it possible to reduce the cost of learning by offering an interface with all the references and modifications that a standard may have, but is not enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within this framework, about 15 years ago I began an exercise to compile and update tax regulations, from which a Draft Tax Code emerged that may be relevant in an economy depressed by COVID. Although it is clearly outdated, perhaps it can be restarted if there is enough interest from society, which at the time there was not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is always talk of a tax reform, but in general the pharaonic work that matters is underestimated, this being perhaps the time to unify criteria, update concepts and order the accounts, with the hope of having rules of the game that encourage investment, development and improve the quality of life for all, reducing costs for citizens and increasing efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can access a preview of this work here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://leobelen.github.io/pdfs/apcta_main.pdf&#34;&gt;Draft Tax Code&lt;/a&gt; (in Spanish).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you like it and find it useful as an interesting starting point.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
