<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tax Administration Rules on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/tags/tax-administration-rules/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tax Administration Rules on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2024, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/tags/tax-administration-rules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: Discard the use of paper as documentary support</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-12-26-descartando-el-papel-como-soporte-documental/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-12-26-descartando-el-papel-como-soporte-documental/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Although throughout history the natural support for documents was on paper, the truth is that this system has major disadvantages against new and better ways using computerized document management systems, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is prone to counterfeiting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It cannot be easily indexed (it can be indexed by hand, but at a very high cost), which generates unnecessary human input for its processing and prevents process automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a support that does not allow you to easily obtain backups of it (except for photocopies), so the loss or degradation of it requires requesting copies from the other party (in this case, the economic actor), with the risks that this entails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a medium that makes transparency difficult, since there can only be n copies of a file at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there are new methodologies that allow not only to guarantee the authenticity of the documents in it, but also in a transparent way for the end user, allowing these documents to be viewed from anywhere. In the same way, the documents included in these methodologies usually force a predefined structure (in other words, forms), which allows the automation of processes and indexing by different fields, which allows a fast and efficient operation and better auditing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, such methodologies have an Achilles heel in paper-based documents, since they are completely blind to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: It is better to do before than after</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-11-16-es-mejor-hacer-antes-que-despues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-11-16-es-mejor-hacer-antes-que-despues/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Human beings are very prone to making mistakes and forgetting things, especially in repetitive tasks. Therefore, it is much more efficient to use automated means - whenever possible - and try to have good quality information from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, this requires very intense work at first, but ensures relaxation later. In some administrations, a very strong inertia has been observed, which discourages the use of proven technologies and methodologies that can greatly help to control information, since they view these efforts as &amp;quot;unnecessary&amp;quot; or too costly, for example processing information from third parties. The reality is that the more it materializes before, the less effort will be necessary later, since the information will have fewer errors and inconsistencies, which normally results in a substantial improvement in collection at a significantly lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special case, which is especially seen in smaller administrations and is more likely to fail, is that of the completeness of the taxpayer registry. In these cases, only taxpayers who are already liable for a tax are registered, so these administrations are blind to those potential taxpayers who are not registered, with the consequent loss of resources derived from those actors who operate only in the informal economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: Taxpayers do not want to pay taxes</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-22-nadie-quiere-pagar-impuestos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-22-nadie-quiere-pagar-impuestos/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;It is normal to forget this concept, but the truth is that it is not usual for some taxpayers to want to comply with their tax obligations voluntarily. However, in addition to being the least numerous, they are actually those that do not represent a collection problem for the administration and, of course, in the long term, all taxpayers are expected to voluntarily comply with their obligations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to outline the universe of taxpayers as a pyramid, in such a way that the large taxpayers are at the top (since they are the least numerous), the medium-sized taxpayers in the center and the small taxpayers and those operators of the informal economy at the bottom. base. In this scenario, it is important to bear in mind that a general objective of a State is to ensure that the greatest number of economic actors progressively migrate towards the top of the pyramid, given that their progress is the progress of society as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following this line, it is possible to outline that an efficient tax system is one that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;has clear, simple rules and is expressed in a language that an average citizen can understand,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is transparent with its requirements and guidelines, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is predictable over time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: Do not create  or raise taxes until all processes are optimized</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-16-no-crear-impuestos-hasta-optimizar-procesos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-16-no-crear-impuestos-hasta-optimizar-procesos/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Although it is recurrent to try to cover public spending by increasing rates or creating new taxes, the reality is that - in general - this does not have the desired effect if the tax administration problems have not been solved beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for this is that although it is easier to carry out such action in the short term (raising a tax or creating it is normally a law and a form), in the medium and long term it generates great social discontent - given that by not increasing the only ones who were already paying the others will be subject to the new tax - and a tax cannibalization of other taxes. It can be said that tax cannibalization occurs when a taxpayer chooses whether to comply with their taxes when the tax pressure is excessive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, in no way does this imply that there are no ways to increase tax collection, but that it is necessary to improve all collection processes and once that route has been exhausted, only consider an increase in rates or the introduction of a new tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a minimum, the following tasks should be accomplished:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure that the tax base or universe of taxpayers is registered in its entirety, in order to avoid economic actors who should declare and pay but escape the tax task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;review and discard those debts that due to statute of limitations or proven uncollectibility are impossible to recover, in order to lighten the work of the collection areas and accelerate recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review and increase collection tasks for those taxpayers with tax debts, particularly in the friendly or administrative collection process when it exists because it is more expeditious. In the same sense, increase the tasks of omission management, to ensure that those taxpayers who are obliged to declare and do not do so, comply with that obligation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze the impact of tax changes on taxpayers through statistics and simulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: Do not only believe the Taxpayer</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-15-no-creer-solo-contribuyente/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-15-no-creer-solo-contribuyente/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;This is perhaps the number one rule of the tax administration and the one that impacts most of the activities, since it invites to verify, in the most efficient and automatic way possible, what is indicated by the taxpayer in his interaction with the administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether due to ignorance, deliberate omission or negligence, it is likely that any given taxpayer will not be in a position to report a given value to the administration with 100% percent certainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this represents a serious problem for the administration, the reality is that it can be further mitigated by implementing cross-checks, that is, defining information channels that can be automatically validated. For example, if a taxpayer is required to declare the requested amount as a mortgage (something usual in the case of Income Tax, or, in Argentina, Income Tax), a channel with banking entities can be used to determine if the taxpayer has requested that amount from a bank and thus validate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, this requires a large amount of information to be available to verify these data, and if well designed it can be done automatically by the Administration, reducing costs and disputes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
