<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>International Cooperation on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/tags/international-cooperation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in International Cooperation on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2024, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/tags/international-cooperation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>International Cooperation: Tendencies</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-09-11-tendencias-en-cooperacion-internacional/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-09-11-tendencias-en-cooperacion-internacional/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;In international cooperation, there are several emerging trends that are influencing the way it is carried out. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs): The SDGs, adopted by the United Nations in 2015, have gained great momentum and are guiding the international cooperation agenda. Cooperation efforts focus on addressing the 17 SDGs, ranging from eradicating poverty and hunger, to promoting gender equality, climate action and access to education and health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results-based development cooperation: There is a growing emphasis on impact measurement and accountability in international cooperation. The aim is to ensure that programs and projects are effective and generate tangible and measurable results in terms of development. This involves establishing performance indicators, conducting periodic evaluations, and using the results to improve practices and decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovation and technology: Innovation and technology are playing an increasingly important role in international cooperation. Innovative and technological solutions are explored to address development challenges, such as the use of artificial intelligence, mobile technology and digital platforms to improve access to basic services, humanitarian aid delivery and natural resource management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public-private collaboration: There is growing collaboration between the public and private sectors in international cooperation. Partnerships between governments, businesses, nonprofits, and civil society are emerging to address common challenges and leverage the resources and expertise of each sector. This includes public-private partnerships for infrastructure projects, corporate social responsibility programs and collaborations in areas such as health, education and entrepreneurship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resilience and risk management focus: With the increase in natural disasters, conflicts and climate challenges, international cooperation is increasingly focusing on building resilience and risk management. This involves strengthening countries&#39; capacity to resist, adapt and recover from crises, and promoting disaster risk reduction and climate change adaptation strategies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These trends reflect the evolution of international cooperation towards a more results-focused, sustainable, innovative and collaborative approach. As global challenges become more complex, these trends are expected to continue influencing the way international cooperation is carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are waiting for you in comments.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Cooperation: Origins of the Funds</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-05-31-cooperacion-internacional-el-origen-de-los-fondos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-05-31-cooperacion-internacional-el-origen-de-los-fondos/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all aid received is the same and within the framework of International Technical Cooperation (ITC) this is no different. This post will deal only with the ITC, which is characterized by being non-reimbursable, unlike the funds granted by the Credit Agencies (CA) - for example the World Bank - as a loan. In the ITC, funds are not obtained, but inputs such as consultancies, equipment, training, technology transfer, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a note of color, we will not present real cases, not to confuse them, but as a measure of protection for the parties involved. If necessary, we will take the case exposed in the work &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-tax-administration/p&#34;&gt;Principles of Tax Administration&lt;/a&gt; (In Spanish) of the People&#39;s Republic and Metropolis as a base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;funds-origin&#34;&gt;Fund&#39;s Origin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;international-government-cooperation-igc&#34;&gt;International Government Cooperation (IGC)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s imagine that a country wants to help a third party through cooperation. It does this with its own resources, originating from the collection of taxes from its citizens, once their needs are covered. However, since resources are finite, the donor country must prioritize aid based on its strategic objectives, which may be economic, social, environmental or other. Then, Bilateral Technical Cooperation (BTC) is called that which occurs directly between two countries, a donor of funds and a recipient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be the case that - depending on the objectives - the participation of several donors may be necessary for a single recipient, something that can occur in the African continent, forming something that we will call Mixed Bilateral Cooperation (MBC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both in the case of the BTC and the MBC, the management of these resources is carried out through the competent organizations in matters of cooperation of the different donor countries, such as the International Cooperation Agencies (ICA). As an example we can cite &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usaid.gov&#34;&gt;USAID&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.giz.de/en/html/index.html&#34;&gt;giz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it may be the case that several countries come together to promote the advancement of a common axis in what we will call Multilateral Technical Cooperation (MTC), forming Multilateral Organizations for International Cooperation (MOIC). These organizations receive contributions from all their members, based on parameters such as the gross domestic product or GDP (ie, the higher the GDP, the greater the contribution) for channeling them to the different recipients. In other words, in these cases both the donor and recipient countries make contributions to the MOIC, based on the variables approved by the members to determine them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both in the BTC and in the MBC or the MTC, the donor&#39;s interest in the progress of the program on which the funds are based clearly emerges. Ultimately these are funds from taxpayers that could have financed goods and services within their borders but chose to do so elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-governmental-international-cooperation-ngic&#34;&gt;Non-Governmental International Cooperation (NGIC)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases it is not governments that donate the funds, but may also be non-governmental actors (for example, foundations), whose origin may be civil society donors, such as private banks. We will call these entities Non-Governmental Organizations (NGOs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;quick-recap&#34;&gt;Quick Recap&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on all of the above, we can say that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The funds donated arise mainly from taxes that the donor collected or was able to collect and that he was able to use to finance programs within his borders but chose to do so through International Cooperation projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In return for these funds, the donor must explain to its citizens the progress of the program and therefore has an interest in knowing its progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the funds are finite, the donor prioritizes the destination based on their needs and those of the recipients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All member countries of an MOIC make a contribution, which depends on the amount based on pre-existing parameters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In no case do funds from non-reimbursable contributions come from nowhere, but are always based on taxes collected or that could be collected. In other words, the donations are based on the funds that certain countries (the donors) decided to invest in others with less relative development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, it is possible to determine that a program will be viable if the following two conditions are true:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The donor country has the funds earmarked for ITC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cooperation program is aligned both with the objectives and policies of the donor and the recipient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hear you in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Financing in Government and Staff Behaviour</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-05-15-financiamiento-internacional-estructuras-gubernamentales-comportamiento-funcionarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-05-15-financiamiento-internacional-estructuras-gubernamentales-comportamiento-funcionarios/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h1 id=&#34;some-definitions&#34;&gt;Some Definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of this post on the basic principles of international financing, the term &amp;quot;Credit Agency (CA)&amp;quot; will be the one that grants a loan to a State, and the one that grants non-reimbursable resources &amp;quot;International Cooperation Agency or donor (ICA)&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between both sources is that a loan (CA) must be repaid by the State and a cooperation resource (ICA) is non-reimbursable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both loans (CA) and grants (ICA) are structured through a project or program, depending on the grantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the loans (CA) must be repaid by the receiving State, they carry an interest that we will call original and one or more punitive interest in case of sub-execution. We will call sub-execution the circumstance in which the objectives defined within the project have not been met in a timely manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the cases of non-reimbursable resources from International Cooperation agencies (ICA), these translate into obtaining: hiring consultancies, training or equipment related to the objectives of the project and the achievement of its results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth repeating: for a Government, it is safe to assume that the resources (both CA and ICA) are never freely available to the receiving country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;structuring-of-funds&#34;&gt;Structuring of funds&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, if these funds are not freely available except within the framework of what is established in the project, what use are they? In principle, they represent a very effective means of advancing on key issues for a Government with the help of others who have already traveled the path before, allowing them to do so in less time and at a lower total cost. For example, if a Government desires to provide its citizens with a Comprehensive Health Service (CHS), it can request help from Canada (through its Cooperation agency (ICA), &lt;a href=&#34;https://cidpnsi.ca&#34;&gt;CanadaAid&lt;/a&gt; ), in the hope that it will share your experiences and sponsor its implementation, something that can be significantly more efficient than implementing the policy alone. In this case, of course &lt;a href=&#34;https://cidpnsi.ca&#34;&gt;CanadaAid&lt;/a&gt; would have an audit power over the development of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can also happen that politically unstable states request a credit agency (CA) for a loan (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://iadb.org&#34;&gt;Inter-American Development Bank - IADB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldbank.org&#34;&gt;World Bank - WB&lt;/a&gt;, among others) for the sole purpose of stabilizing and guaranteeing the execution of a priority policy for the country. This, because upon receiving the funds, they also accept the external review of the grantor, who can apply sanctions for non-compliance with the project&#39;s objectives (punitive interests other than the original ones).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it can be affirmed that the funds can only be granted through the approval of a project, which implies a detailed description of the objectives to be achieved, the stipulated execution period and the assigned resources (budget). On a recurring basis, the project is carried out by a local execution unit, which, if it does not have installed capacity, can be an international organization (such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://undp.org&#34;&gt;United Nations Program for Development and Sustainable Life - UNDP&lt;/a&gt;), or a combination of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is to say, everything is oriented towards a tight control of the finances and the objectives of the project, given that it is exercised by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the receiving State&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the project execution unit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The organization originating the funds, whether they are multilateral lending banks, regional banks and/or bilateral donors (CA and ICA).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others involved (stakeholders)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-special-requests&#34;&gt;The &amp;quot;special requests&amp;quot;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is sometimes curious that in many jurisdictions, government officials do not seem to understand that the resources granted by these organizations (CA and ICA) cannot be used to cover expenses not related to the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have seen in some cases that, faced with this reality, officials try to make requests outside the project, in some cases we have observed how conferences have been organized in 5-star hotels not provided for in the project budget, or the hiring of a venue has been required unqualified but highly influential in key positions as a requirement for its continuity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sense, it may happen that the receiving Government understands that the political and short-term objective takes precedence over the objective of the project but using resources for results not foreseen in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally, the organizations (both CA and ICA) do not grant funds for current expenses, such as salaries of public employees, electricity or gas bills, among others, financing in some cases only very short-term expert consultancies (for example 2 weeks) so that they can transmit their knowledge to the receiving State, usually with little impact, especially in cases of high staff turnover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-can-a-state-do-with-the-funds-granted-by-an-international-organization&#34;&gt;What can a State do with the funds granted by an international organization?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the funds have been granted and the project approved, it can be assumed that the negotiation stage is over, so that only what is included in the project can be executed. Sometimes, government officials do not understand this premise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth remembering that both the CAs and the ACIs can contribute to the achievement of the priority policies of the recipient country, which in turn are framed within the objectives of said organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hear you in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Help to Finance  Projects in Government: International Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-01-31-buscando-ayuda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-01-31-buscando-ayuda/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Welcome to a new year with a very interesting topic: The financing methods of Government institutions. I mean, not so much for its content, but the distance between what the common people believe and what it really is. For this article we have the help of one of the greatest specialists in International Cooperation in Argentina, Dr. Raquel Deas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to implementing changes in Government structures, financial resources determine almost all of the scope, since if funds are scarce or are not stable over time they will simply make the project unfeasible. In this sense, we can indicate that there are different forms of financing, for example International Cooperation, which will be discussed in this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;international-cooperation&#34;&gt;International Cooperation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, in jurisdictions that qualify for this type of funding, international cooperation entities (or donors) will provide non-reimbursable funds for Goverment Modernization and improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sense, it is necessary to point out that these &amp;quot;non-reimbursable funds&amp;quot; translate into the transfer of knowledge and technologies between countries and/or multilateral organizations, generally through inputs (consulting, equipment, and/or technical material and training).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simplified classification of the international cooperation sources can be determined on the actors involved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Governmental
      &lt;ol&gt;
         &lt;li&gt; Bilateral
         &lt;ol&gt;
             &lt;li&gt; North-South: developed countries to less developed countries (colloquially coined ads &#34;first to third world&#34; funding).
             &lt;li&gt; South-South: countries of similar or equal relative development.
         &lt;/ol&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;Multilateral
             &lt;ol&gt;
                 &lt;li&gt; Global Organizations, mostly part of the UN, including UNDP, UNOPS and UNIDO.
                 &lt;li&gt;Regional Organizations, such as the OAS and regional tax organizations such as IOTA and CATA.
             &lt;/ol&gt;
         &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Non-Governmental
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is executed by Organisms, Associations, Foundations (collectively called NGOs).
&lt;li&gt;This type of cooperation also obeys political, social, economic, environmental, religious, and cultural interests, among others.
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International cooperation scenarios are very dynamic at a global level in terms of objectives, volumes, beneficiaries and modalities, all of them subject to the conditionality of the different providers (economic, political, environmental and other priority criteria). This conditionality must be observed by the receiving States at the time of negotiation, making their priorities compatible with their feasibility in the global framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These scenarios must be observed by the receiving States when searching for sources in accordance with national priorities and their feasibility in the global framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pros-and-cons-of-international-cooperation&#34;&gt;Pros and cons of international cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Strengths&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Opportunities&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• It allows modernization processes without monetary or budgetary cost for Government.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• In the long term, it can improve Government services.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• In case of political instability, this type of financing can allow the continuity of the project.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Weaknesses&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Threats&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Possible influence on the direction of the modernization project with the guidelines of the grantor of cooperation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Cooperation may be jeopardized if the expected results are not obtained.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Technical cooperation may respond more to the interests (political, sale of technology, among others) of the donor than to the recipient&#39;s priorities.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Interference in internal affairs by the grantor of the cooperation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
