<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Principles on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/tags/principles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Principles on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2024, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/tags/principles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Behavior Moderation Principle</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-10-15-principio-de-moderacion-del-comportamiento/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-10-15-principio-de-moderacion-del-comportamiento/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;The tax system is - from the behavioral perspective - an incentive system, since States can use it to promote or discourage economic activities that it considers strategic. For example, a State may consider encouraging the services sector by alleviating taxes that affect it and discouraging the consumption of alcoholic beverages by creating a tax on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing it from this principle, any increase or decrease in tax burdens has an impact not only on the treasury coffers but on the entire economy.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Savings Allocation Principle</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-14-principio-de-afectacion-del-ahorro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-14-principio-de-afectacion-del-ahorro/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;The amounts paid as taxes mainly affect the savings capacity of the affected taxpayers. In other words, if the tax pressure rises to a level that exceeds the savings capacity, it is expected that there will come a time when a taxpayer no longer complies with his tax obligations, forcing him to enter a &amp;ldquo;fiscal snowball&amp;rdquo;, a situation where, in the best scenario, he will subscribe to successive payment plans for the tax debts incurred until completely cease the debt based on the immensity of the debt based on their income.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Transparency Principle in a Tax Administration</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-13-principio-de-transparencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-13-principio-de-transparencia/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;The principle of transparency refers to the fact that all the actors involved in a transaction with the administration can check its sources, including returns, accounting statements and process data, depending on their level of responsibility in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This principle does not contradict the fiscal secrecy since it does not propose exposing the economic actor but simply allowing him to share the information held in the administration about himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantages derived from this principle are much greater than its disadvantages, among which we can mention:&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
