<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Principles on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/tags/principles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Principles on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2024, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/tags/principles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Behavior Moderation Principle</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-10-15-principio-de-moderacion-del-comportamiento/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-10-15-principio-de-moderacion-del-comportamiento/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;The tax system is - from the behavioral perspective - an incentive system, since States can use it to promote or discourage economic activities that it considers strategic. For example, a State may consider encouraging the services sector by alleviating taxes that affect it and discouraging the consumption of alcoholic beverages by creating a tax on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing it from this principle, any increase or decrease in tax burdens has an impact not only on the treasury coffers but on the entire economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Savings Allocation Principle</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-14-principio-de-afectacion-del-ahorro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-14-principio-de-afectacion-del-ahorro/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;The amounts paid as taxes mainly affect the savings capacity of the affected taxpayers. In other words, if the tax pressure rises to a level that exceeds the savings capacity, it is expected that there will come a time when a taxpayer no longer complies with his tax obligations, forcing him to enter a &amp;quot;fiscal snowball&amp;quot;, a situation where, in the best scenario, he will subscribe to successive payment plans for the tax debts incurred until completely cease the debt based on the immensity of the debt based on their income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, the optimal tax pressure operates on the surpluses that would otherwise go to savings. From this it follows that a tax burden that goes beyond these surpluses is doomed to failure, since even those who in good faith want to comply with it, will not be able to do so without dispensing with making other payments that are necessary, unnecessarily increasing the costs of collection and greatly affecting social dissatisfaction. Keep in mind that humans do not have a choice about whether or not to feed, and in extreme cases this activity will clearly be prioritized over any imposed load. In other words, if an individual is forced between fulfilling his tax obligations and paying for his basic needs, he will understandably always choose the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Transparency Principle in a Tax Administration</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-13-principio-de-transparencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-13-principio-de-transparencia/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;The principle of transparency refers to the fact that all the actors involved in a transaction with the administration can check its sources, including returns, accounting statements and process data, depending on their level of responsibility in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This principle does not contradict the fiscal secrecy since it does not propose exposing the economic actor but simply allowing him to share the information held in the administration about himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantages derived from this principle are much greater than its disadvantages, among which we can mention:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allows a cross and detailed control, significantly improving the efficiency of the tax administration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;facilitates communication between the economic actor and the administration, since both parties can freely consult all the events that have taken place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;greatly restricts the arbitrariness perceived by economic actors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the application of this principle can be intimidating at first if it has never been implemented, but the truth is that its long-term benefits fully justify its incorporation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
