<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strategy on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/tags/strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strategy on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2024, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/tags/strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Traps to Avoid in Goverment</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2025-07-03-fallas-comunes-a-evitar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2025-07-03-fallas-comunes-a-evitar/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;In their book &lt;em&gt;If We Can Put a Man on the Moon&lt;/em&gt;, Eggers and O&amp;rsquo;Leary&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; identify seven critical traps that are highly relevant to the formulation of an effective strategy in Goverment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Tolstoy Trap (Tolstoy Syndrome)&lt;/em&gt;: Seeing only what you want to see and ignoring inconvenient facts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Design-Free Design Trap&lt;/em&gt;: Designing policies for legislative passage, not for real-world implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Stargate Trap (Partial Map Trap)&lt;/em&gt;: Fumbling handoffs and lacking clear execution plans throughout project delivery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Overconfidence Trap&lt;/em&gt;: Creating unrealistic budgets and timelines due to excessive optimism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Sisyphus Trap&lt;/em&gt;: Repeatedly pushing the same initiative without learning from past failures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Complacency Trap&lt;/em&gt;: Failing to recognize when a program needs change or improvement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Silo Trap&lt;/em&gt;: Allowing organizational silos to block information flow and collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;specific-tax-administration-traps-to-avoid&#34;&gt;Specific Tax Administration Traps to Avoid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Associated with these pitfalls is one that directly affects the tax administration function, which can be referred to as the &lt;em&gt;Early Tax Introduction Trap&lt;/em&gt;. This trap is characterized by the introduction of a new tax, or an increase in the rate of an existing tax, before fully exhausting the tax base - in other words, before ensuring that all taxpayers who are required to declare and pay taxes have been properly registered and accounted for.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective Tax Administration in the Developing World: Strategies for Maximizing Revenue with Limited Resources</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-10-administracion-tributaria-eficaz-paises-vias-desarrollo-estrategias-maximizar-ingresos-recursos-limitados/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-10-administracion-tributaria-eficaz-paises-vias-desarrollo-estrategias-maximizar-ingresos-recursos-limitados/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Tax administration is a crucial component of any government&amp;rsquo;s fiscal policy, as it provides the necessary revenue to fund public services and infrastructure. However, in the developing world, tax administration often faces significant challenges due to limited resources, corruption, and inadequate infrastructure. In this blog post, we will explore the key areas to prioritize when aiming to improve tax collection with minimal resources and discuss the sole area that should be set as the priority in extreme cases.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
