<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/categories/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2022, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/categories/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mexico and BEPS</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-09-mexico-y-beps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-09-mexico-y-beps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;A few years ago a company that offers an accounting program in the United States asked me to evaluate the impact of BEPS in Mexico. From that study, which was much more than what they expected, this mini paper came out that you can consult &lt;a href=&#34;https://leobelen.github.io/pdfs/mexico_beps_premier.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://vixra.org/abs/1811.0098&#34;&gt;originally published here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of the human factor in a paradigmatic change in Tax Administrations</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2021-07-15-impacto-del-factor-humano-en-un-cambio-paradigm%C3%A1tico-en-las-administraciones-tributarias/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2021-07-15-impacto-del-factor-humano-en-un-cambio-paradigm%C3%A1tico-en-las-administraciones-tributarias/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;This thesis was motivated by the lack of specific literature for organizational change in state structures mainly dedicated to tax administration, which has generated a culture of empiricism that can be clearly appreciated in different parts of the world, as will be seen during the developing. In principle, today the &amp;quot;engine of change&amp;quot; par excellence turns out to be technology (that is, the implementation of an ITAS or administrative management program), however, this factor is one among many others. In particular, this thesis was carried out in order to analyze the impact of the human factor on paradigmatic changes in tax administrations and the improvements that can be introduced to maximize them. For this, the applicable theory was analyzed and surveys have been carried out in different administrations (including organizations in Argentina, Guatemala and Barbados) and a series of interviews with specialists in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can consult it in &lt;a href=&#34;https://repositorio.utdt.edu/handle/utdt/1683&#34;&gt;the online library of the Torcuato Di Tella university&lt;/a&gt; (in Spanish).&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Argentum</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2021-02-23-argentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2021-02-23-argentum/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Some time ago, together with Alejandro Baranek, after a meeting with the creators of a digital currency called &lt;a href=&#34;https://monedapar.com.ar&#34;&gt;Moneda Par&lt;/a&gt;, we developed the theoretical framework for a digital currency that would solve some of the existing problems in Argentina at that time, mainly inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, Argentum emerged, whose paper can be consulted &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1912.09569&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible Socioeconomic Analysis over SDMX</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2017-10-04-estudios-sociocon%C3%B3micos-sobre-sdmx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2017-10-04-estudios-sociocon%C3%B3micos-sobre-sdmx/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;A paper that we presented in 2017 at the SDMX conference in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, on socio-economic studies on SDMX. You can see the resulting paper &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/cros/system/files/proof_of_concept_of_reproducible_socioeconomic_analysis_over_sdmx_paper.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the original presentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/cros/system/files/proof_of_concept_of_reproducible_socioeconomic_analysis_over_sdmx_presentation_0.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
