<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OECD on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/tags/oecd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OECD on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2024, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/tags/oecd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Borders: How OECD Pillar Two is Reshaping Global Tax Administration</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2026-02-05-mas-alla-de-las-fronteras-como-el-segundo-pilar-de-la-ocde-esta-transformando-la-administracion-tributaria-global/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2026-02-05-mas-alla-de-las-fronteras-como-el-segundo-pilar-de-la-ocde-esta-transformando-la-administracion-tributaria-global/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-the-dawn-of-a-new-tax-era&#34;&gt;Introduction: The Dawn of a New Tax Era&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 8 October 2021, the OECD/G20 Inclusive Framework on Base Erosion and Profit Shifting (BEPS) reached a historic consensus: 136 jurisdictions agreed to implement a two-pillar solution addressing the tax challenges arising from digitalisation of the economy.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; While Pillar One focuses on reallocating taxing rights for the largest digitalised businesses, &lt;strong&gt;Pillar Two has emerged as the more universally applicable—and administratively complex—component of this global tax reform&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing Tax Administration: The Power of Digitalization in Achieving OECD Pillars and BEPS Objectives</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-12-02-revolucionando-la-administracion-tributaria-el-poder-de-la-digitalizacion-para-alcanzar-los-pilares-de-la-ocde-y-los-objetivos-beps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-12-02-revolucionando-la-administracion-tributaria-el-poder-de-la-digitalizacion-para-alcanzar-los-pilares-de-la-ocde-y-los-objetivos-beps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;In an era of rapid technological advancement, tax administrations worldwide are embracing digitalization to enhance efficiency, improve compliance, and tackle the challenges posed by the evolving global economy. This blog explores how tax authorities can leverage digital transformation to support OECD pillars and BEPS objectives, highlights best practices, and examines cases where implementation faced hurdles and how they were overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-digital-transformation-of-tax-administration&#34;&gt;The Digital Transformation of Tax Administration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital transformation of tax administration is no longer a choice but a necessity in today&amp;rsquo;s interconnected world. As economies increasingly digitalize, tax authorities must adapt to changing business models, consumer behaviors, and expectations. The goal of this transformation is to make taxation easier and less costly for taxpayers while ensuring the right amount of tax is collected&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administration in the Development World: A Key to Achieving OECD Pillar 2 Objectives</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-17-administracion-tributaria-en-el-mundo-en-desarrollo-una-clave-para-alcanzar-los-objetivos-del-pilar-2-de-la-ocde/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2024-06-17-administracion-tributaria-en-el-mundo-en-desarrollo-una-clave-para-alcanzar-los-objetivos-del-pilar-2-de-la-ocde/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Tax administration plays a crucial role in the development of any country. It is responsible for ensuring that taxes are collected and distributed fairly and efficiently, which in turn supports economic growth and social welfare. In recent years, the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) has emphasized the importance of tax administration in achieving its Pillar 2 objectives, which aim to ensure that multinational corporations (MNCs) pay their fair share of taxes. This blog post will explore the relationship between tax administration and OECD Pillar 2 objectives, as well as provide guidance on how to set priorities effectively in the context of tax administration.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
