<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/tags/theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theory on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2024, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/tags/theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>International Cooperation: Tendencies</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-09-11-tendencias-en-cooperacion-internacional/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-09-11-tendencias-en-cooperacion-internacional/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;In international cooperation, there are several emerging trends that are influencing the way it is carried out. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs): The SDGs, adopted by the United Nations in 2015, have gained great momentum and are guiding the international cooperation agenda. Cooperation efforts focus on addressing the 17 SDGs, ranging from eradicating poverty and hunger, to promoting gender equality, climate action and access to education and health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results-based development cooperation: There is a growing emphasis on impact measurement and accountability in international cooperation. The aim is to ensure that programs and projects are effective and generate tangible and measurable results in terms of development. This involves establishing performance indicators, conducting periodic evaluations, and using the results to improve practices and decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovation and technology: Innovation and technology are playing an increasingly important role in international cooperation. Innovative and technological solutions are explored to address development challenges, such as the use of artificial intelligence, mobile technology and digital platforms to improve access to basic services, humanitarian aid delivery and natural resource management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public-private collaboration: There is growing collaboration between the public and private sectors in international cooperation. Partnerships between governments, businesses, nonprofits, and civil society are emerging to address common challenges and leverage the resources and expertise of each sector. This includes public-private partnerships for infrastructure projects, corporate social responsibility programs and collaborations in areas such as health, education and entrepreneurship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resilience and risk management focus: With the increase in natural disasters, conflicts and climate challenges, international cooperation is increasingly focusing on building resilience and risk management. This involves strengthening countries&#39; capacity to resist, adapt and recover from crises, and promoting disaster risk reduction and climate change adaptation strategies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These trends reflect the evolution of international cooperation towards a more results-focused, sustainable, innovative and collaborative approach. As global challenges become more complex, these trends are expected to continue influencing the way international cooperation is carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are waiting for you in comments.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Cooperation: Origins of the Funds</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-05-31-cooperacion-internacional-el-origen-de-los-fondos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-05-31-cooperacion-internacional-el-origen-de-los-fondos/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all aid received is the same and within the framework of International Technical Cooperation (ITC) this is no different. This post will deal only with the ITC, which is characterized by being non-reimbursable, unlike the funds granted by the Credit Agencies (CA) - for example the World Bank - as a loan. In the ITC, funds are not obtained, but inputs such as consultancies, equipment, training, technology transfer, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a note of color, we will not present real cases, not to confuse them, but as a measure of protection for the parties involved. If necessary, we will take the case exposed in the work &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-tax-administration/p&#34;&gt;Principles of Tax Administration&lt;/a&gt; (In Spanish) of the People&#39;s Republic and Metropolis as a base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;funds-origin&#34;&gt;Fund&#39;s Origin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;international-government-cooperation-igc&#34;&gt;International Government Cooperation (IGC)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s imagine that a country wants to help a third party through cooperation. It does this with its own resources, originating from the collection of taxes from its citizens, once their needs are covered. However, since resources are finite, the donor country must prioritize aid based on its strategic objectives, which may be economic, social, environmental or other. Then, Bilateral Technical Cooperation (BTC) is called that which occurs directly between two countries, a donor of funds and a recipient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be the case that - depending on the objectives - the participation of several donors may be necessary for a single recipient, something that can occur in the African continent, forming something that we will call Mixed Bilateral Cooperation (MBC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both in the case of the BTC and the MBC, the management of these resources is carried out through the competent organizations in matters of cooperation of the different donor countries, such as the International Cooperation Agencies (ICA). As an example we can cite &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usaid.gov&#34;&gt;USAID&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.giz.de/en/html/index.html&#34;&gt;giz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it may be the case that several countries come together to promote the advancement of a common axis in what we will call Multilateral Technical Cooperation (MTC), forming Multilateral Organizations for International Cooperation (MOIC). These organizations receive contributions from all their members, based on parameters such as the gross domestic product or GDP (ie, the higher the GDP, the greater the contribution) for channeling them to the different recipients. In other words, in these cases both the donor and recipient countries make contributions to the MOIC, based on the variables approved by the members to determine them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both in the BTC and in the MBC or the MTC, the donor&#39;s interest in the progress of the program on which the funds are based clearly emerges. Ultimately these are funds from taxpayers that could have financed goods and services within their borders but chose to do so elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-governmental-international-cooperation-ngic&#34;&gt;Non-Governmental International Cooperation (NGIC)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases it is not governments that donate the funds, but may also be non-governmental actors (for example, foundations), whose origin may be civil society donors, such as private banks. We will call these entities Non-Governmental Organizations (NGOs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;quick-recap&#34;&gt;Quick Recap&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on all of the above, we can say that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The funds donated arise mainly from taxes that the donor collected or was able to collect and that he was able to use to finance programs within his borders but chose to do so through International Cooperation projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In return for these funds, the donor must explain to its citizens the progress of the program and therefore has an interest in knowing its progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the funds are finite, the donor prioritizes the destination based on their needs and those of the recipients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All member countries of an MOIC make a contribution, which depends on the amount based on pre-existing parameters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In no case do funds from non-reimbursable contributions come from nowhere, but are always based on taxes collected or that could be collected. In other words, the donations are based on the funds that certain countries (the donors) decided to invest in others with less relative development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, it is possible to determine that a program will be viable if the following two conditions are true:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The donor country has the funds earmarked for ITC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cooperation program is aligned both with the objectives and policies of the donor and the recipient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hear you in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Financing in Government and Staff Behaviour</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-05-15-financiamiento-internacional-estructuras-gubernamentales-comportamiento-funcionarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-05-15-financiamiento-internacional-estructuras-gubernamentales-comportamiento-funcionarios/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h1 id=&#34;some-definitions&#34;&gt;Some Definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of this post on the basic principles of international financing, the term &amp;quot;Credit Agency (CA)&amp;quot; will be the one that grants a loan to a State, and the one that grants non-reimbursable resources &amp;quot;International Cooperation Agency or donor (ICA)&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between both sources is that a loan (CA) must be repaid by the State and a cooperation resource (ICA) is non-reimbursable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both loans (CA) and grants (ICA) are structured through a project or program, depending on the grantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the loans (CA) must be repaid by the receiving State, they carry an interest that we will call original and one or more punitive interest in case of sub-execution. We will call sub-execution the circumstance in which the objectives defined within the project have not been met in a timely manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the cases of non-reimbursable resources from International Cooperation agencies (ICA), these translate into obtaining: hiring consultancies, training or equipment related to the objectives of the project and the achievement of its results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth repeating: for a Government, it is safe to assume that the resources (both CA and ICA) are never freely available to the receiving country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;structuring-of-funds&#34;&gt;Structuring of funds&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, if these funds are not freely available except within the framework of what is established in the project, what use are they? In principle, they represent a very effective means of advancing on key issues for a Government with the help of others who have already traveled the path before, allowing them to do so in less time and at a lower total cost. For example, if a Government desires to provide its citizens with a Comprehensive Health Service (CHS), it can request help from Canada (through its Cooperation agency (ICA), &lt;a href=&#34;https://cidpnsi.ca&#34;&gt;CanadaAid&lt;/a&gt; ), in the hope that it will share your experiences and sponsor its implementation, something that can be significantly more efficient than implementing the policy alone. In this case, of course &lt;a href=&#34;https://cidpnsi.ca&#34;&gt;CanadaAid&lt;/a&gt; would have an audit power over the development of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can also happen that politically unstable states request a credit agency (CA) for a loan (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://iadb.org&#34;&gt;Inter-American Development Bank - IADB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.worldbank.org&#34;&gt;World Bank - WB&lt;/a&gt;, among others) for the sole purpose of stabilizing and guaranteeing the execution of a priority policy for the country. This, because upon receiving the funds, they also accept the external review of the grantor, who can apply sanctions for non-compliance with the project&#39;s objectives (punitive interests other than the original ones).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it can be affirmed that the funds can only be granted through the approval of a project, which implies a detailed description of the objectives to be achieved, the stipulated execution period and the assigned resources (budget). On a recurring basis, the project is carried out by a local execution unit, which, if it does not have installed capacity, can be an international organization (such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://undp.org&#34;&gt;United Nations Program for Development and Sustainable Life - UNDP&lt;/a&gt;), or a combination of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is to say, everything is oriented towards a tight control of the finances and the objectives of the project, given that it is exercised by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the receiving State&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the project execution unit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The organization originating the funds, whether they are multilateral lending banks, regional banks and/or bilateral donors (CA and ICA).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Others involved (stakeholders)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-special-requests&#34;&gt;The &amp;quot;special requests&amp;quot;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is sometimes curious that in many jurisdictions, government officials do not seem to understand that the resources granted by these organizations (CA and ICA) cannot be used to cover expenses not related to the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have seen in some cases that, faced with this reality, officials try to make requests outside the project, in some cases we have observed how conferences have been organized in 5-star hotels not provided for in the project budget, or the hiring of a venue has been required unqualified but highly influential in key positions as a requirement for its continuity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sense, it may happen that the receiving Government understands that the political and short-term objective takes precedence over the objective of the project but using resources for results not foreseen in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally, the organizations (both CA and ICA) do not grant funds for current expenses, such as salaries of public employees, electricity or gas bills, among others, financing in some cases only very short-term expert consultancies (for example 2 weeks) so that they can transmit their knowledge to the receiving State, usually with little impact, especially in cases of high staff turnover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-can-a-state-do-with-the-funds-granted-by-an-international-organization&#34;&gt;What can a State do with the funds granted by an international organization?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the funds have been granted and the project approved, it can be assumed that the negotiation stage is over, so that only what is included in the project can be executed. Sometimes, government officials do not understand this premise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth remembering that both the CAs and the ACIs can contribute to the achievement of the priority policies of the recipient country, which in turn are framed within the objectives of said organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hear you in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Change Tools in Government Structures</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-04-18-herramientas-del-cambio-organizacional-en-estructuras-del-estado/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-04-18-herramientas-del-cambio-organizacional-en-estructuras-del-estado/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Some of the most useful tools within the organizational change arsenal are not available (or their implementation is so complicated as to make it unfeasible) in State structures. Thus, staff dismissal, the tool to eliminate &lt;em&gt;rebellion focus&lt;/em&gt;, is normally contraindicated. We can say that a &lt;em&gt;rebellion focus&lt;/em&gt; is any pocket of resistance to change within the organization. Based on this, in general terms, the following tools are available instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Process automation&lt;/em&gt;: This tool is focused on studying those processes already running at the organzation, how support systems can be implemented, along with all the associated changes (legislation, internal regulations, personnel assignment, etc. ) to improve the efficiency of a process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internal promotion campaign&lt;/em&gt;: This tool must be initiated even before starting the change tasks themselves. It must be focused on convincing current staff that the paradigm in use is insufficient to face the new challenges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charismatic internal champions&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Rebellion foci&lt;/em&gt; can be neutralized in many cases with internal change leaders (or champions) who raise the need to participate in the proposed change. In general, the best internal champions are those who were opponents in the past, since they are not only convinced of the change but also know the approaches of the opponents in detail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Training under the new paradigm&lt;/em&gt;: A paradigmatic change does not happen from one day to the next and for many employees it is impossible to assimilate without external help, since this change implies an abandonment of the old practices. For them, the training tasks are necessary to help them move onto the new paradigm. This training must cover not only its most outstanding aspects (such as systems or legal framework) but also its motivations and reasons. In addition, it must be continuous in time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Voluntary retirement&lt;/em&gt;: A common &lt;em&gt;rebellion focus&lt;/em&gt; is given by those who are in their last years of professional life and do not wish to change the methodology under any circumstances since they assume that with it they also change who they are. For them, a departure may be a voluntary retirement scheme that encourages them to leave the organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Referral to a different area within the organization&lt;/em&gt;: If none of the above work, then a last-resort option is to move the problematic staff member to an area where he does not have to experience the full force of the organizational change, so that he does not feel the full impact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other tools are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Help to Finance  Projects in Government: International Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-01-31-buscando-ayuda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-01-31-buscando-ayuda/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Welcome to a new year with a very interesting topic: The financing methods of Government institutions. I mean, not so much for its content, but the distance between what the common people believe and what it really is. For this article we have the help of one of the greatest specialists in International Cooperation in Argentina, Dr. Raquel Deas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to implementing changes in Government structures, financial resources determine almost all of the scope, since if funds are scarce or are not stable over time they will simply make the project unfeasible. In this sense, we can indicate that there are different forms of financing, for example International Cooperation, which will be discussed in this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;international-cooperation&#34;&gt;International Cooperation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, in jurisdictions that qualify for this type of funding, international cooperation entities (or donors) will provide non-reimbursable funds for Goverment Modernization and improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this sense, it is necessary to point out that these &amp;quot;non-reimbursable funds&amp;quot; translate into the transfer of knowledge and technologies between countries and/or multilateral organizations, generally through inputs (consulting, equipment, and/or technical material and training).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simplified classification of the international cooperation sources can be determined on the actors involved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Governmental
      &lt;ol&gt;
         &lt;li&gt; Bilateral
         &lt;ol&gt;
             &lt;li&gt; North-South: developed countries to less developed countries (colloquially coined ads &#34;first to third world&#34; funding).
             &lt;li&gt; South-South: countries of similar or equal relative development.
         &lt;/ol&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;Multilateral
             &lt;ol&gt;
                 &lt;li&gt; Global Organizations, mostly part of the UN, including UNDP, UNOPS and UNIDO.
                 &lt;li&gt;Regional Organizations, such as the OAS and regional tax organizations such as IOTA and CATA.
             &lt;/ol&gt;
         &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Non-Governmental
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is executed by Organisms, Associations, Foundations (collectively called NGOs).
&lt;li&gt;This type of cooperation also obeys political, social, economic, environmental, religious, and cultural interests, among others.
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International cooperation scenarios are very dynamic at a global level in terms of objectives, volumes, beneficiaries and modalities, all of them subject to the conditionality of the different providers (economic, political, environmental and other priority criteria). This conditionality must be observed by the receiving States at the time of negotiation, making their priorities compatible with their feasibility in the global framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These scenarios must be observed by the receiving States when searching for sources in accordance with national priorities and their feasibility in the global framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pros-and-cons-of-international-cooperation&#34;&gt;Pros and cons of international cooperation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Strengths&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Opportunities&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• It allows modernization processes without monetary or budgetary cost for Government.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• In the long term, it can improve Government services.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• In case of political instability, this type of financing can allow the continuity of the project.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Weaknesses&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Threats&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Possible influence on the direction of the modernization project with the guidelines of the grantor of cooperation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Cooperation may be jeopardized if the expected results are not obtained.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Technical cooperation may respond more to the interests (political, sale of technology, among others) of the donor than to the recipient&#39;s priorities.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Interference in internal affairs by the grantor of the cooperation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: Discard the use of paper as documentary support</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-12-26-descartando-el-papel-como-soporte-documental/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-12-26-descartando-el-papel-como-soporte-documental/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Although throughout history the natural support for documents was on paper, the truth is that this system has major disadvantages against new and better ways using computerized document management systems, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is prone to counterfeiting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It cannot be easily indexed (it can be indexed by hand, but at a very high cost), which generates unnecessary human input for its processing and prevents process automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a support that does not allow you to easily obtain backups of it (except for photocopies), so the loss or degradation of it requires requesting copies from the other party (in this case, the economic actor), with the risks that this entails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a medium that makes transparency difficult, since there can only be n copies of a file at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there are new methodologies that allow not only to guarantee the authenticity of the documents in it, but also in a transparent way for the end user, allowing these documents to be viewed from anywhere. In the same way, the documents included in these methodologies usually force a predefined structure (in other words, forms), which allows the automation of processes and indexing by different fields, which allows a fast and efficient operation and better auditing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, such methodologies have an Achilles heel in paper-based documents, since they are completely blind to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: It is better to do before than after</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-11-16-es-mejor-hacer-antes-que-despues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-11-16-es-mejor-hacer-antes-que-despues/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Human beings are very prone to making mistakes and forgetting things, especially in repetitive tasks. Therefore, it is much more efficient to use automated means - whenever possible - and try to have good quality information from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, this requires very intense work at first, but ensures relaxation later. In some administrations, a very strong inertia has been observed, which discourages the use of proven technologies and methodologies that can greatly help to control information, since they view these efforts as &amp;quot;unnecessary&amp;quot; or too costly, for example processing information from third parties. The reality is that the more it materializes before, the less effort will be necessary later, since the information will have fewer errors and inconsistencies, which normally results in a substantial improvement in collection at a significantly lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special case, which is especially seen in smaller administrations and is more likely to fail, is that of the completeness of the taxpayer registry. In these cases, only taxpayers who are already liable for a tax are registered, so these administrations are blind to those potential taxpayers who are not registered, with the consequent loss of resources derived from those actors who operate only in the informal economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Behavior Moderation Principle</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-10-15-principio-de-moderacion-del-comportamiento/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-10-15-principio-de-moderacion-del-comportamiento/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;The tax system is - from the behavioral perspective - an incentive system, since States can use it to promote or discourage economic activities that it considers strategic. For example, a State may consider encouraging the services sector by alleviating taxes that affect it and discouraging the consumption of alcoholic beverages by creating a tax on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing it from this principle, any increase or decrease in tax burdens has an impact not only on the treasury coffers but on the entire economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: Taxpayers do not want to pay taxes</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-22-nadie-quiere-pagar-impuestos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-22-nadie-quiere-pagar-impuestos/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;It is normal to forget this concept, but the truth is that it is not usual for some taxpayers to want to comply with their tax obligations voluntarily. However, in addition to being the least numerous, they are actually those that do not represent a collection problem for the administration and, of course, in the long term, all taxpayers are expected to voluntarily comply with their obligations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to outline the universe of taxpayers as a pyramid, in such a way that the large taxpayers are at the top (since they are the least numerous), the medium-sized taxpayers in the center and the small taxpayers and those operators of the informal economy at the bottom. base. In this scenario, it is important to bear in mind that a general objective of a State is to ensure that the greatest number of economic actors progressively migrate towards the top of the pyramid, given that their progress is the progress of society as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following this line, it is possible to outline that an efficient tax system is one that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;has clear, simple rules and is expressed in a language that an average citizen can understand,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is transparent with its requirements and guidelines, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is predictable over time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: Do not create  or raise taxes until all processes are optimized</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-16-no-crear-impuestos-hasta-optimizar-procesos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-16-no-crear-impuestos-hasta-optimizar-procesos/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;Although it is recurrent to try to cover public spending by increasing rates or creating new taxes, the reality is that - in general - this does not have the desired effect if the tax administration problems have not been solved beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for this is that although it is easier to carry out such action in the short term (raising a tax or creating it is normally a law and a form), in the medium and long term it generates great social discontent - given that by not increasing the only ones who were already paying the others will be subject to the new tax - and a tax cannibalization of other taxes. It can be said that tax cannibalization occurs when a taxpayer chooses whether to comply with their taxes when the tax pressure is excessive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, in no way does this imply that there are no ways to increase tax collection, but that it is necessary to improve all collection processes and once that route has been exhausted, only consider an increase in rates or the introduction of a new tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a minimum, the following tasks should be accomplished:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure that the tax base or universe of taxpayers is registered in its entirety, in order to avoid economic actors who should declare and pay but escape the tax task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;review and discard those debts that due to statute of limitations or proven uncollectibility are impossible to recover, in order to lighten the work of the collection areas and accelerate recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review and increase collection tasks for those taxpayers with tax debts, particularly in the friendly or administrative collection process when it exists because it is more expeditious. In the same sense, increase the tasks of omission management, to ensure that those taxpayers who are obliged to declare and do not do so, comply with that obligation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze the impact of tax changes on taxpayers through statistics and simulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: Do not only believe the Taxpayer</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-15-no-creer-solo-contribuyente/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-15-no-creer-solo-contribuyente/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;This is perhaps the number one rule of the tax administration and the one that impacts most of the activities, since it invites to verify, in the most efficient and automatic way possible, what is indicated by the taxpayer in his interaction with the administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether due to ignorance, deliberate omission or negligence, it is likely that any given taxpayer will not be in a position to report a given value to the administration with 100% percent certainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this represents a serious problem for the administration, the reality is that it can be further mitigated by implementing cross-checks, that is, defining information channels that can be automatically validated. For example, if a taxpayer is required to declare the requested amount as a mortgage (something usual in the case of Income Tax, or, in Argentina, Income Tax), a channel with banking entities can be used to determine if the taxpayer has requested that amount from a bank and thus validate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, this requires a large amount of information to be available to verify these data, and if well designed it can be done automatically by the Administration, reducing costs and disputes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Savings Allocation Principle</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-14-principio-de-afectacion-del-ahorro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-14-principio-de-afectacion-del-ahorro/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;The amounts paid as taxes mainly affect the savings capacity of the affected taxpayers. In other words, if the tax pressure rises to a level that exceeds the savings capacity, it is expected that there will come a time when a taxpayer no longer complies with his tax obligations, forcing him to enter a &amp;quot;fiscal snowball&amp;quot;, a situation where, in the best scenario, he will subscribe to successive payment plans for the tax debts incurred until completely cease the debt based on the immensity of the debt based on their income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, the optimal tax pressure operates on the surpluses that would otherwise go to savings. From this it follows that a tax burden that goes beyond these surpluses is doomed to failure, since even those who in good faith want to comply with it, will not be able to do so without dispensing with making other payments that are necessary, unnecessarily increasing the costs of collection and greatly affecting social dissatisfaction. Keep in mind that humans do not have a choice about whether or not to feed, and in extreme cases this activity will clearly be prioritized over any imposed load. In other words, if an individual is forced between fulfilling his tax obligations and paying for his basic needs, he will understandably always choose the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Transparency Principle in a Tax Administration</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-13-principio-de-transparencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-13-principio-de-transparencia/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;p&gt;The principle of transparency refers to the fact that all the actors involved in a transaction with the administration can check its sources, including returns, accounting statements and process data, depending on their level of responsibility in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This principle does not contradict the fiscal secrecy since it does not propose exposing the economic actor but simply allowing him to share the information held in the administration about himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantages derived from this principle are much greater than its disadvantages, among which we can mention:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allows a cross and detailed control, significantly improving the efficiency of the tax administration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;facilitates communication between the economic actor and the administration, since both parties can freely consult all the events that have taken place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;greatly restricts the arbitrariness perceived by economic actors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the application of this principle can be intimidating at first if it has never been implemented, but the truth is that its long-term benefits fully justify its incorporation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other principles are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
