<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://leobelen.github.io/tags/theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theory on Leonardo Belén&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017-2024, Leonardo Javier Belén; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leobelen.github.io/tags/theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>International Cooperation: Tendencies</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-09-11-tendencias-en-cooperacion-internacional/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-09-11-tendencias-en-cooperacion-internacional/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;In international cooperation, there are several emerging trends that are influencing the way it is carried out. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs): The SDGs, adopted by the United Nations in 2015, have gained great momentum and are guiding the international cooperation agenda. Cooperation efforts focus on addressing the 17 SDGs, ranging from eradicating poverty and hunger, to promoting gender equality, climate action and access to education and health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results-based development cooperation: There is a growing emphasis on impact measurement and accountability in international cooperation. The aim is to ensure that programs and projects are effective and generate tangible and measurable results in terms of development. This involves establishing performance indicators, conducting periodic evaluations, and using the results to improve practices and decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovation and technology: Innovation and technology are playing an increasingly important role in international cooperation. Innovative and technological solutions are explored to address development challenges, such as the use of artificial intelligence, mobile technology and digital platforms to improve access to basic services, humanitarian aid delivery and natural resource management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public-private collaboration: There is growing collaboration between the public and private sectors in international cooperation. Partnerships between governments, businesses, nonprofits, and civil society are emerging to address common challenges and leverage the resources and expertise of each sector. This includes public-private partnerships for infrastructure projects, corporate social responsibility programs and collaborations in areas such as health, education and entrepreneurship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resilience and risk management focus: With the increase in natural disasters, conflicts and climate challenges, international cooperation is increasingly focusing on building resilience and risk management. This involves strengthening countries&#39; capacity to resist, adapt and recover from crises, and promoting disaster risk reduction and climate change adaptation strategies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These trends reflect the evolution of international cooperation towards a more results-focused, sustainable, innovative and collaborative approach. As global challenges become more complex, these trends are expected to continue influencing the way international cooperation is carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Cooperation: Origins of the Funds</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-05-31-cooperacion-internacional-el-origen-de-los-fondos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-05-31-cooperacion-internacional-el-origen-de-los-fondos/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all aid received is the same and within the framework of International Technical Cooperation (ITC) this is no different. This post will deal only with the ITC, which is characterized by being non-reimbursable, unlike the funds granted by the Credit Agencies (CA) - for example the World Bank - as a loan. In the ITC, funds are not obtained, but inputs such as consultancies, equipment, training, technology transfer, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Financing in Government and Staff Behaviour</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-05-15-financiamiento-internacional-estructuras-gubernamentales-comportamiento-funcionarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-05-15-financiamiento-internacional-estructuras-gubernamentales-comportamiento-funcionarios/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;h1 id=&#34;some-definitions&#34;&gt;Some Definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of this post on the basic principles of international financing, the term &amp;quot;Credit Agency (CA)&amp;quot; will be the one that grants a loan to a State, and the one that grants non-reimbursable resources &amp;quot;International Cooperation Agency or donor (ICA)&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between both sources is that a loan (CA) must be repaid by the State and a cooperation resource (ICA) is non-reimbursable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both loans (CA) and grants (ICA) are structured through a project or program, depending on the grantor.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Change Tools in Government Structures</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-04-18-herramientas-del-cambio-organizacional-en-estructuras-del-estado/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-04-18-herramientas-del-cambio-organizacional-en-estructuras-del-estado/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Some of the most useful tools within the organizational change arsenal are not available (or their implementation is so complicated as to make it unfeasible) in State structures. Thus, staff dismissal, the tool to eliminate &lt;em&gt;rebellion focus&lt;/em&gt;, is normally contraindicated. We can say that a &lt;em&gt;rebellion focus&lt;/em&gt; is any pocket of resistance to change within the organization. Based on this, in general terms, the following tools are available instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Process automation&lt;/em&gt;: This tool is focused on studying those processes already running at the organzation, how support systems can be implemented, along with all the associated changes (legislation, internal regulations, personnel assignment, etc. ) to improve the efficiency of a process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internal promotion campaign&lt;/em&gt;: This tool must be initiated even before starting the change tasks themselves. It must be focused on convincing current staff that the paradigm in use is insufficient to face the new challenges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charismatic internal champions&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Rebellion foci&lt;/em&gt; can be neutralized in many cases with internal change leaders (or champions) who raise the need to participate in the proposed change. In general, the best internal champions are those who were opponents in the past, since they are not only convinced of the change but also know the approaches of the opponents in detail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Training under the new paradigm&lt;/em&gt;: A paradigmatic change does not happen from one day to the next and for many employees it is impossible to assimilate without external help, since this change implies an abandonment of the old practices. For them, the training tasks are necessary to help them move onto the new paradigm. This training must cover not only its most outstanding aspects (such as systems or legal framework) but also its motivations and reasons. In addition, it must be continuous in time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Voluntary retirement&lt;/em&gt;: A common &lt;em&gt;rebellion focus&lt;/em&gt; is given by those who are in their last years of professional life and do not wish to change the methodology under any circumstances since they assume that with it they also change who they are. For them, a departure may be a voluntary retirement scheme that encourages them to leave the organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Referral to a different area within the organization&lt;/em&gt;: If none of the above work, then a last-resort option is to move the problematic staff member to an area where he does not have to experience the full force of the organizational change, so that he does not feel the full impact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This and other tools are available in the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://tienda.thomsonreuters.com.ar/978-987-03-4377-6%E2%80%8B-principios-de-administracion-tributaria/p&#34;&gt;Principios de Administración Tributaria&lt;/a&gt; published by Thomson Reuters - La Ley.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Help to Finance  Projects in Government: International Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-01-31-buscando-ayuda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2023-01-31-buscando-ayuda/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Welcome to a new year with a very interesting topic: The financing methods of Government institutions. I mean, not so much for its content, but the distance between what the common people believe and what it really is. For this article we have the help of one of the greatest specialists in International Cooperation in Argentina, Dr. Raquel Deas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to implementing changes in Government structures, financial resources determine almost all of the scope, since if funds are scarce or are not stable over time they will simply make the project unfeasible. In this sense, we can indicate that there are different forms of financing, for example International Cooperation, which will be discussed in this post.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: Discard the use of paper as documentary support</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-12-26-descartando-el-papel-como-soporte-documental/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-12-26-descartando-el-papel-como-soporte-documental/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Although throughout history the natural support for documents was on paper, the truth is that this system has major disadvantages against new and better ways using computerized document management systems, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is prone to counterfeiting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It cannot be easily indexed (it can be indexed by hand, but at a very high cost), which generates unnecessary human input for its processing and prevents process automation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a support that does not allow you to easily obtain backups of it (except for photocopies), so the loss or degradation of it requires requesting copies from the other party (in this case, the economic actor), with the risks that this entails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a medium that makes transparency difficult, since there can only be n copies of a file at the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there are new methodologies that allow not only to guarantee the authenticity of the documents in it, but also in a transparent way for the end user, allowing these documents to be viewed from anywhere. In the same way, the documents included in these methodologies usually force a predefined structure (in other words, forms), which allows the automation of processes and indexing by different fields, which allows a fast and efficient operation and better auditing.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: It is better to do before than after</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-11-16-es-mejor-hacer-antes-que-despues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-11-16-es-mejor-hacer-antes-que-despues/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Human beings are very prone to making mistakes and forgetting things, especially in repetitive tasks. Therefore, it is much more efficient to use automated means - whenever possible - and try to have good quality information from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, this requires very intense work at first, but ensures relaxation later. In some administrations, a very strong inertia has been observed, which discourages the use of proven technologies and methodologies that can greatly help to control information, since they view these efforts as &amp;quot;unnecessary&amp;quot; or too costly, for example processing information from third parties. The reality is that the more it materializes before, the less effort will be necessary later, since the information will have fewer errors and inconsistencies, which normally results in a substantial improvement in collection at a significantly lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Behavior Moderation Principle</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-10-15-principio-de-moderacion-del-comportamiento/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-10-15-principio-de-moderacion-del-comportamiento/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;The tax system is - from the behavioral perspective - an incentive system, since States can use it to promote or discourage economic activities that it considers strategic. For example, a State may consider encouraging the services sector by alleviating taxes that affect it and discouraging the consumption of alcoholic beverages by creating a tax on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing it from this principle, any increase or decrease in tax burdens has an impact not only on the treasury coffers but on the entire economy.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: Taxpayers do not want to pay taxes</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-22-nadie-quiere-pagar-impuestos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-22-nadie-quiere-pagar-impuestos/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;It is normal to forget this concept, but the truth is that it is not usual for some taxpayers to want to comply with their tax obligations voluntarily. However, in addition to being the least numerous, they are actually those that do not represent a collection problem for the administration and, of course, in the long term, all taxpayers are expected to voluntarily comply with their obligations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to outline the universe of taxpayers as a pyramid, in such a way that the large taxpayers are at the top (since they are the least numerous), the medium-sized taxpayers in the center and the small taxpayers and those operators of the informal economy at the bottom. base. In this scenario, it is important to bear in mind that a general objective of a State is to ensure that the greatest number of economic actors progressively migrate towards the top of the pyramid, given that their progress is the progress of society as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: Do not create  or raise taxes until all processes are optimized</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-16-no-crear-impuestos-hasta-optimizar-procesos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-16-no-crear-impuestos-hasta-optimizar-procesos/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;Although it is recurrent to try to cover public spending by increasing rates or creating new taxes, the reality is that - in general - this does not have the desired effect if the tax administration problems have not been solved beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for this is that although it is easier to carry out such action in the short term (raising a tax or creating it is normally a law and a form), in the medium and long term it generates great social discontent - given that by not increasing the only ones who were already paying the others will be subject to the new tax - and a tax cannibalization of other taxes. It can be said that tax cannibalization occurs when a taxpayer chooses whether to comply with their taxes when the tax pressure is excessive.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Administrations&#39; Rules: Do not only believe the Taxpayer</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-15-no-creer-solo-contribuyente/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-15-no-creer-solo-contribuyente/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;This is perhaps the number one rule of the tax administration and the one that impacts most of the activities, since it invites to verify, in the most efficient and automatic way possible, what is indicated by the taxpayer in his interaction with the administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether due to ignorance, deliberate omission or negligence, it is likely that any given taxpayer will not be in a position to report a given value to the administration with 100% percent certainty.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Savings Allocation Principle</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-14-principio-de-afectacion-del-ahorro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-14-principio-de-afectacion-del-ahorro/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;The amounts paid as taxes mainly affect the savings capacity of the affected taxpayers. In other words, if the tax pressure rises to a level that exceeds the savings capacity, it is expected that there will come a time when a taxpayer no longer complies with his tax obligations, forcing him to enter a &amp;quot;fiscal snowball&amp;quot;, a situation where, in the best scenario, he will subscribe to successive payment plans for the tax debts incurred until completely cease the debt based on the immensity of the debt based on their income.&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Transparency Principle in a Tax Administration</title>
      <link>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-13-principio-de-transparencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leobelen.github.io/post/2022-09-13-principio-de-transparencia/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            &lt;p&gt;The principle of transparency refers to the fact that all the actors involved in a transaction with the administration can check its sources, including returns, accounting statements and process data, depending on their level of responsibility in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This principle does not contradict the fiscal secrecy since it does not propose exposing the economic actor but simply allowing him to share the information held in the administration about himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantages derived from this principle are much greater than its disadvantages, among which we can mention:&lt;/p&gt;
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
